FARZAD ROOZITALAB

Ottawa, Canada

 \blacksquare (+1)343-297-1413 \diamond \blacksquare farzadroozitalab@cmail.carleton.ca \diamond \blacksquare Linkedin \diamond \bigcirc Farzad-R

KEY COMPETENCIES

Machine Learning (ML) & Deep Learning (DL) - Optimization - Data science - Time-series forecasting - Renewable energies - R&D - Teamwork

SUMMARY

Research assistant, teacher assistant, and AI workshop lead at Carleton University. Spent one year at Tessella (Capgemini Engineering) as an ML engineer and consultant. Collaborated with different research groups at Politecnico di Milano (Italy), University of Pavia (Italy), Beihang University (China), and Carleton University (Canada). Has strong teamwork skills and passion to work on ML projects and learn new concepts.

WORK EXPERIENCES

1.	\mathbf{AI}	Workshop	Lead

© Carleton Artificial Intelligence Society (CAIS)
 Research Assistant & Teacher Assistant

@ Carleton University

3. Junior Consultant

@ Capgemini Engineering (Tessella)

Role: Machine learning engineer and data scientist

4. Junior Electrical Engineer

@ Niroo Gostar Fars

Project: Doroodzan - Shiraz, water pipeline design

Sep 2022 - Now (Volunteer_PT)

Ottawa - Canada

Jan 2022 - Now (FT)

Ottawa - Canada

Feb 2021 - Dec 2021 (FT)

Milan - Italy

Feb 2015 - Nov 2016 (FT)

Shiraz - Iran

EDUCATION

Carleton University (Ottawa - Canada)

2022 - Present

- Granted full NSERC Doctoral Scholarship
- Degree: Ph.D in Mechanical and Aerospace Engineering
- Research title: Development of physics-informed deep learning models for atmospheric fluid dynamics

Politecnico di Milano University (Milan - Italy)

2017 - 2020

- Degree: MSc in Electrical Engineering
- Thesis title: Development of a multi-Task protection algorithm for fault detection, classification, and fault line identification in DC Microgrids

Azad University of Marvdasht (Shiraz - Iran)

2011 - 2013

- Degree: BSc in Electrical Engineering

Bahonar University of Technology

2009 - 2010

- Degree: Associate Degree in General Electronics

PROGRAMMING AND SOFTWARE CAPABILITIES

Machine Learning and Deep Learning:

- Some tasks: Timeseries forecasting Anomaly and fault detection Classification Supervised, semi supervised, and unsupervised learning, Transfer learning
- Some Deep architectures: Attention based models Transformers (Informer, Autoformer, Spacetimeformer)
- Auto-encoders (Convolution based GRU/LSTM based) ResNet
- Probabilistic models: DeepAR DeepFactor Multi-Horizon Quantile Recurrent Forecaster (MQRNN)
- Some ML models: SVM XGBoost LightGBM CatBoost Random forest KNN

Some libraries: Tensorflow, Keras, PyTorch, Darts, scikit-learn, mlFlow Optimization:

- Some algorithms: Genetic Algorithm - Evolutionary Programming - Differential evolution - Tabu search - Particle Swarm optimization - Salp swarm Optimization

Python:

- Some tasks: ML and DL design, Object Oriented Programming, debugging, and testing
- $\boldsymbol{\mathsf{-}}$ $\boldsymbol{\mathsf{Some}}$ $\boldsymbol{\mathsf{packages:}}$ mlFlow, Luigi, poetry, pipenv, conda, unittest, pytest

R:

- Some tasks: ML design, Data science, Package design, Shiny dashboard
- Some Libraries: tidyverse, dplyr, purr, ggplot2, Mlr, caret, knitr, Janitor, etc.

Version control: Git, AWS CodeCommit MATLAB: Programming and Simulink

SQLite LATEX

SELECTED PUBLICATIONS

- 1. Jarrahi, M. A., Roozitalab, F., Arefi, M. M., Javadi, M. S., Moghaddam, A. A., & Catalão, J. P. (2020). DC Microgrid Energy Management System Containing Photovoltaic Sources Considering Supercapacitor and Battery Storages. 3rd International Conference on Smart Energy Systems and Technologies (SEST), Istanbul, Turkey.
- 2. Roozitalab, F., Jarrahi, M. A., Arefi, M. M., Javadi, M. S., Moghaddam, A. A., & Catalão, J. P. (2020). Development of A Hybrid Method to Control the Grid-Connected PV Converter. 2020 EEEIC International Conference on Environment and Electrical Engineering, Madrid, Spain (pp. 1-6). IEEE Press.
- 3. Li, G., Li, Y., & Roozitalab, F. (2020). Mid-term Load Forecasting: A Multi-step Approach Based on Phase Space Reconstruction and Support Vector Machine. IEEE Systems Journal.

CERTIFICATIONS

SQL for Data Science

University of California, Davis - 2022

Deep Learning Specialization:

Deeplearning.ai - 2021

- Neural Network and Deep Learning/Improving Deep Neural Networks: Hyperparameter Tuning, Regularization and Optimization/ Structuring Machine Learning Projects/ Convolutional Neural Networks/ Sequence Models

Machine Learning Engineering for Production Specialization: (GC) Deeplearning.ai - 2021

- Introduction to Machine Learning in Production/ Machine Learning Data Lifecycle in Production/ Machine Learning Modeling Pipelines in Production/ Deploying Machine Learning Models in Production

Practical Data Science Specialization: (AWS)

Deeplearning.ai & AWS -2021

- Analyze Datasets and Train ML Models using AutoML/ Build, Train, and Deploy ML Pipelines using BERT/ Optimize ML Models and Deploy Human-in-the-Loop Pipelines

TensorFlow 2 for Deep Learning Specialization:

Imperial College London - 2021

- Getting started with Tensor Flow 2/ Customising your models with Tensor Flow 2/ Probabilistic Deep Learning with Tensor Flow 2

Sequences, Time Series and Prediction

Deeplearning.ai - 2021

Practical Time Series Analysis

The state university of New York - 2021

Mining Data from Time Series Pluralsight - 2021

Building Data Pipelines with Luigi and Python Pluralsight - 2021

Core python - Object Oriented Programming

Pluralsight - 2021

Advanced Python

Pluralsight - 2021

Data Science with R

Pluralsight - 2021

Exploratory Data Analysis with R

Pluralsight - 2021

Data Analysis with Shiny: R Playbook Pluralsight - 2021

LANGUAGES

English: Professional Proficiency, Italian: Elementary, Persian: Native